[airplane, radio transmissions]
(Captain Over Radio)...request
permission to enter US airspace.
(Virginia Vallejo) I've had to
leave a house in the middle of
the night because
of a man before...
but this is the first time
I've had to leave a country.
(Tower Over Radio) 7221,
you are cleared to enter.
(Captain) Okay, folks,
we are now entering
United States airspace.
(Shepard) You're safe now.
(Virginia)
I've made this trip before.
There were always dozens
of white roses waiting
for me in every suite but
the men waiting at the door
did not wear uniforms.
They wore Armani.
So, Virginia over the next few
days you'll nneet with officials
from the Justice Department and
they will inform you of the
procedure to follow from now on.
Can someone get me
an aspirin please?
My head is going to explode.
(Holland) Ma'am, for your own
safety, you do not leave this
room or communicate with anyone.
I have two of my men
standing outside.
Do you understand?
Can you get them to bring
me an aspirin please?
Virginia, American hotels don't
give out aspirin anymore.
It's considered a
drug in this country.
[laughs]
(Virginia VO) Pablo would
have laughed at that, too.
Then he would have
had them all killed.
♪♪
[crash, neighing horse]
(Careta) We have to
finish him, Patrón.
[cocking guns]
(Escobar) Do it, Pelao.
[neighing]
[gun shot]
(Escobar)
Did you see the guest list?
(Victoria) Hmm. It's
full of beautiful women.
Colombia is full of
beautiful women, my love.
It's a party.
Actresses, beauty queens.
And soccer players,
union delegates.
You are much more beautiful.
Look.
Than the union delegates?
Look who's coming.
I don't like it, Pablo.
Business and family separate.
We already talked about it.
I know, I know.
With the party,
everything is a little bit of
a mess. I'll take care of it.
[door closes]
(Salvador) I have the
triggerman you asked for.
I'll talk to him, and
you take him away.
I don't want him around.
Don Pablo.
If you can find this coin,
you can keep it. Go for it.
I have a little
job for you in Leticia.
There's a file from seven years
ago linking me to the murder
of two DAS agents. You have
to make it disappear, okay?
Everything you find.
Leave it nice and clean.
Listen, you have
contacts there, right?
My cousin's wife works
at the courthouse.
She can get me in.
There's no problem.
...Dad?
...I don't care if you have to
take out somebody, or what you
have to do. You can burn the
building down if you want...
but get rid of that file.
You have 30,000 for expenses,
for travelling, for ammunition,
for rumba, for everything.
If you run out, ask
Salvador for more. He will...
...Dad!
...take care of everything.
...Go on then. Go on.
...You got it, boss.
You find the coin?
It's only five pesos.
It's only five pesos? Don
Pablo, you know how hard
your daddy has to work
to make some money?
Give it back.
Only five pesos.
♪♪
Is that the hacienda down there?
(Victor) We've been flying
over it for a while, my love.
We're getting kidnapped!
It's okay, Virgie. Calm down.
It's not okay.
Do you know how much all
of us here are worth?
(VO) We'd all heard
about or host,
but none of us had ever met him.
His name is at the top of the
list of the nouveau riche.
A group of young men that
have made huge fortunes
in very little time.
Welcome.
Please don't mind the weapons,
they're there for the animals.
We have a little zoo here.
You like to see it?
You scared us to death.
Tell our host, this is
no way to welcome guests.
As soon as I see him.
[elephant trumpets]
(Chantal) Oh, my God.
They're beautiful.
They're very happy here.
They like Colombia.
That's because they
don't read the papers.
This house is gigantic.
I don't see the
servants anywhere.
There you have them.
(VO) This new elite has
its own social structure.
Down in the corridors, the
soldiers, young, uneducated men
from the slums, warriors
in the organization.
They're nothing like the humble
servants working on the ranches
of the traditionally rich
people in my country.
They are confident.
They handle security
and operations, and...
...have good taste in women.
(Woman) Virginia,
I never miss your show!
You look so beautiful.
(VO) Above them, the cream.
Artists, businessmen, soccer
players, journalists, models.
Always a perfect distance
away from our host.
Cover your ears, Victor.
There are so many
handsome guys here.
Thank you.
Anyone who's anyone is here.
Where does he
make all this money?
That's the question a
reporter has to ask.
[applause]
Good one, good one, good one!
Virginia. Virginia.
Where have you been hiding?
Pablo keep asking for you.
He's driving us
crazy, so come on.
Victor, wait here.
Don't fall in love with a local.
(VO) And up the hill, the
kings of the white mountain.
We still don't know
their names but soon,
there won't be a single
Colombian who doesn't.
She was easy to find.
I just went where all
the men were looking.
Pablo?
Pablo Escobar?
No.
Your complaints were passed on
to me, so I beg your pardon.
You lied to me.
Good Lord,
of course I lied to you.
I didn't want you to leave.
You look even
prettier in person.
Then I'll have to
fire my makeup girl.
There's a lot of talk
about you over there.
Speculations about your past.
No, no, no, don't
listen to that.
I only listen when they
speculate about my future.
I already know my past.
And what's the occasion?
It's just the
founding of a society.
What kind of society?
Philanthropic. We are
building houses for the poor.
Nobody over
there mentioned to you
No.
Well, were going to build
2,000 homes for the people
at the garbage dump.
I got a very good
price on a lot.
And where does the
money come from?
What, is this an interview?
I'm a journalist.
Then come and see it.
Come and see it.
I'll show it to you.
It's good for the
country to know.
Good for the country
or good for you?
Am I not a part of the country?
(VO) We weren't aware at the
time but that night we were
celebrating the founding
of the Medellin Cartel and the
crowning of Pablo as its king.
Things were about
to change forever...
in Colombia and in my life.
[kids shouting]
Breathe through your mouth
and you get used to it fast.
Watch where you step.
People dump bodies
out here sometimes.
You're kidding.
(Boy) Don Pablo!
Don Pablo!
Is everybody here named Pablo?
(Priest) Everybody.
They named them after him.
Listen, we are now
finishing the first 600 but
we want to build 2000, eh? 2000.
Please tell our viewers the
motivation and goal behind
this wonderful initiative,
Well, It is painful for us to
see so many children starving
completely unprotected
by the government.
And building these
houses for them
helps us to create a country
that we always dreamed about.
I love Colombia, and now
that we have the chance to give
back to this beautiful country
that gave us so much that is
exactly what we're doing.
(VO) That day, I decide that
I don't care how Pablo makes
his money,
only how he uses it.
♪♪
Do you know that people?
[laughs]
I like the way you laugh.
You laugh like on your show.
You are so relaxed on TV.
How do you do that?
Do you think I
could ever do that?
There are tricks.
Are you after my job?
No, I'm not.
Are you married?
Not by choice.
What does he do?
He's a plastic surgeon.
We are separated, but he doesn't
want to sign the divorce.
He doesn't want you
to get married again?
No, he doesn't want
to have to marry one of
his teenage girlfriends.
Aahh.
Well, that can be fixed.
You'll talk to him?
Look I don't like hanging around
with married women. I don't.
So, next time we are going out,
you're not going be his wife.
No?
No.
Will I be his widow?
What do you take me for?
[bell rings]
(A.D.) Everyone ready?
(Paula)
Virginia! Your lawyer called!
Your ex signed the papers!
(A.D.) We are on in three, two...
...What?
(VO) To celebrate
me being free again,
Pablo takes me to an island
paradise only he knows about.
If you're going
to cry over a man,
better in a private
jet than on a bus.
[thumping]
[grunt]
Where are you going?
They're waiting.
Who?
♪♪
Do I look okay?
You look perfect.
(Careta) How's it going, Patrón?
Ma'am.
Let's make a deal,
you tell me your secrets
and I'll tell you mine, okay?
(VO) Our trip is
an excuse to attend a
congress of drug traffickers.
(Monje) Virginia, how are you?
When did you arrive?
Today.
(VO) Pablo introduces me to
his associates in the cartel.
He shows me off to
them like a trophy.
And I know that they're
also there to evaluate me.
Between them, they
form a new social class,
the narco millionaires.
And I'm the only journalist
with exclusive access
to their first summit.
Thank you.
I'm going to get a drink.
Stay close, Virginia. These
men can't be trusted, okay?
(VO) The most illegal thing
I'd ever done before that
day was to double park.
[laughs]
But the truth is never in
my life had I felt safer.
(Cartel Member) All of our
priorities is labeled with a
color that doesn't change.
(VO) That night, they split
the United States of America
among them.
Florida for the Medellin Cartel,
New York for the Cali Cartel.
The independents add their
shipments to Pablo's.
They know that nobody
would ever dare to steal
even one gram from him.
Seeing him in his natural
habitat, is addictive.
Thanks to those men, it is
going to snow cocaine in the US.
[truck horn]
(Woman) Honey, did you see that?
[squealing tires]
[cars honking]
(Driver)
Hey, guys, are you nuts?
What the fuck are you doing?
(Officer) Stuck in a
jam on highway 75 heading
southbound out of Temple.
[low rumble]
Holy shit.
♪♪
(Car Driver) What are you doing?
Are you fucking nuts!
I almost killed you!
(VO) They called them the
saints, because they make the
miracle of
multiplication up there.
Do the math.
One kilo is worth
$7,000 here in Colombia.
In the United States, they cut
it, add lactose and it becomes
three kilos which are
worth 150,000 there.
Is that a miracle or not?
(Man) Oh, my God!
(Woman) Jim, Stop!
[car honking]
(Man) Oh, shit!
♪♪
(TV announcer)
From the White House,
President and
Mrs. Ronald Reagan.
A message on drugs.
(Ronald Reagan) Despite our
best efforts, illegal cocaine
is coming into our country
at alarming levels.
It's especially damaging to
the young people on whom
our future depends. So tonight,
from our family to yours,
from our home to yours
thank you for joining us.
America has accomplished so
much in these last few years...
(Govt Official)
Welcome, Agent Shepard.
The President is glad
to have you on board.
...Thank you.
...This is Mr. Velarde,
representing the
Colombian government.
Nice to meet you.
The President's worried
about the latest report.
Cocaine is no longer the
drug of the jet set,
it's reaching the middle class.
You know what that means.
It's coming in without control.
80 percent is coming
from Colombia.
We're working to have an old
bilateral treaty reactivated.
(Velarde) The Extradition
Treaty. We'll catch the narcos
and turn them over so
you can try them here.
They don't fear the
judges in Colombia,
they either bribe
them or kill them.
But they do fear your justice.
Is there a legal basis for this?
The coke is produced in my
country, but it's consumed here.
The crime is completed
in the United States.
I brought a draft.
The President knows your record.
He wants you to monitor
the whole process.
The President will
be over shortly.
We are hoping to implement
this in the next day or so.
(Nancy Reagan) Drugs take away
the dream from every child's
heart and replace
it with a nightmare.
And it's time
we in America stand up
and replace those dreams.
(Escobar) What are we, children?
Don't we have judges here?
No mother sends her children to
the neighbors to be punished.
No.
(Monje) What do
the lawyers have to say?
Is this constitutional?
Can it be appealed?
(Ignacio Castro)
Yeah, it can be appealed.
We have to knock it down.
That treaty puts us in
danger to everyone here.
Every one of you,
every one of us.
We have to fight it from the
institutions, from inside.
(Hermosilla) From Congress?
It's the only way.
Throw money at them, both sides.
Conservatives and Liberals,
they all like the good stuff.
The spotlight like
this, bad for business.
And whatever they
look for in your house,
they'll find in everyone else's.
(Carlos Corral)
Listen to us, please.
They'll go after you.
Politics is a bitch.
No, hermano.
It's the other way around.
If you reach Congress,
they respect you.
Why? Because you're one of them.
You know how much it costs
to run for state council
in Colombia?
Ten million pesos.
And for Senator I think
it is between 100 and
120 million pesos.
1,500 million pesos more
or less, for president of
the republic. Tell me who
can spend that kind of money?
The son of a farmer?
A worker? No, no.
Politics comes
down to money here.
Democracy comes
So we have plenty of money.
[chuckles]
You, Garza, what's so funny?
(Garza) You should listen
to yourself, Pablito.
You're already talking
like a politician!
[chuckles]
♪♪
Sir, we have an appointment
with the candidate.
(Campaign Manager)
Are they armed?
Why of course they are,
they're my bodyguards.
I'm sorry, sir. If they're
armed, they can't come in.
They're carrying our
donation to your campaign.
If they can't come in,
the donation can't either.
So go ask your candidate
if that's what he wants.
(VO) The cartel
bets on both horses.
Why put money
on only one candidate
when you can put money on both?
That way, no matter
who wins, they win.
The narco's planes carry
candidates during the day
and fly to the United
States at night.
And what do they
get in exchange?
You defend the competency of the
Supreme Court to question the
constitutionality of the
Extradition Treaty,
it will be good for
all of us, Mr. Candidate.
These gentlemen want to donate
25 million pesos to our campaign
here in Antioquia.
(VO) People call the
contributions made by the drug
lords hot money.
Why?
...It's okay.
You can leave it on the floor.
We'll find someone
to pick it up later.
(VO) Because it burns.
♪♪
How far are you
going to take this, Pablo?
We're doing fine.
Don't we have enough?
Mi amor, in Congress
I can get things done,
I can help people, I...
Help your family first.
You have money, Pablo.
You have us.
What more do you want?
I want respect.
Respect?
Mmhmm. I want respect.
I want my son to be proud of me.
Is that so hard to understand?
First, he'd have to see you,
Pablo, but you're never home.
Don Pablo, mi amigo,
go to the living room.
There's nothing on TV?
Good Lord, who
bought him that car?
Victoria, mi amor, don't you
want to be the First Lady?
I'd settle for being
the only lady, Pablo.
Oh, my God.
No, no, again.
She's helping me with
my political campaign.
I want respect, too, Pablo.
Like you.
I respect...
The difference is
yours is enough for me.
I respect you.
No, you don't.
...I do.
...You don't.
I'll prove it.
What do you want me to do? What?
I'll do it. What?
That bitch from TV.
End it with her.
I promise right
now it is over now.
Now.
Right now.
I promise. I promise.
I promise.
It is over.
Give me one
of those laughters.
See, see?
[laughter on TV]
[grunting]
We want a country like a
mother, generous and fertile,
who shares her wealth
equally with her children,
but who always looks
out for the weakest.
[applause]
We want a country like a mother
who defends her children from
foreign aggression
without hesitation.
Severe but understanding.
Long live the mothers of
Colombia and our motherland.
They will cry tears of blood the
day the first son is extradited.
[cheering]
(Tv Anchor)
Let's stay in Antioquia
to see how election
day has gone.
At this time, most of the
votes have been counted.
For Alternativa Popular,
Movimiento de Renovación Liberal
Pablo Escobar Gaviria has been
elected representative of the
house of Medellin.
For Colombia...
[applause]
♪♪
(VO) Senator Escobar is
denied entry the first day he
attends Congress.
Why? Because he smuggles
forty tons of cocaine a
year into the United States?
No.
(House Official) I'm sorry,
sir, but a tie is required
to enter our chamber.
(VO) That's my country for you.
♪♪
What are you doing
looking through my bag?
That's not where you'll
find a picture of my lover.
What's that?
It's a surprise,
surprise for you.
Pablo, take that money
out of my bag right now!
Why?
You're not going to
put me in danger!
I have nothing to do
with your business, okay?
It's a gift for you, Virginia.
This is for you to enjoy it.
A gift.
This is a gift for me?
But, Pablo, that's
a lot of money!
I know, but don't worry.
The American government doesn't
care how much you bring in, it
only cares how
much you take out.
So you can declare it all
when you get to customs.
But it's too much!
I cannot accept it.
Look, it doesn't even fit.
That's the problem,
it doesn't fit.
We have to take out the clothes.
You can buy new ones there, see?
Take them all out.
But you have to spend all the
money, you can't bring anything
back with you, Virginia.
All my life waiting
to hear those words!
(VO) Colombians don't
turn on their TVs to see me,
but what I'm wearing.
Pablo is aware of this, and he
takes care of all my needs.
(Escobar) This is called
coca paste. And the poorest
drug addicts mix it with
gasoline and call it bazook.
This crap will fry your brain.
There's nothing
worse than this.
Now, when you cook it, you
get this little white powder
but it's the same shit.
We work with this, eh?
But we do not take it here.
Have you heard of Nancy Reagan?
No?
She's a very important lady and
she says that if anybody offers
you this stuff, you just say no.
You're going to
listen to that lady.
To her and to your daddy.
You just say no, eh?
Hello. 88, please.
Thank you.
Miss Vallejo?
Do we know each other?
Do you have any plans?
Can I have a moment
of your time?
Do you lack selfconfidence,
Agent Shepard?
[chuckles]
Give me two hours?
Sure.
I saw your interview
with Mr. Escobar.
Thousands of people saw it.
What can you tell me about him?
So disappointing.
You're not interested in me,
you're interested in Pablo.
I'm a married man.
So, you know how
he makes his money?
What does your embassy
over there tell you?
Nothing good.
Well, Mr. Escobar is an elected
government representative.
So I don't think the DEA has any
legal authority to interfere
in Colombian politics.
The drugs produced in your
country are entering mine,
and that worries us.
No.
No. Your government
is only worried about the
money leaving the country
not the drugs that come in.
You don't have this
problem with the Italian Mafia,
because what
they make stays here.
Drug money is different.
It flies away.
That's what worries you.
[puts glass down]
What did he say, Pablo,
when you told him that
you were coming to meet me?
What did he say?
He said to make sure the
United States pays the bill.
You two are involved.
You have the nerve
to ask me that?
Why don't you ask your
friends at the CIA?
I will.
You know what?
I would have
agreed to a drink...
[whispers]
even without the badge.
♪♪
[airplane]
Where's Pablo?
(Monje) He had to go to Bogota.
Congress is holding
a special session.
They want to revoke
his appointment.
They cannot do that.
That bastard Minister of
Justice has it out for us.
He requested the review.
Things are getting
wild, Virginia.
The whole country
is watching us.
We are in the spotlight.
(Rodrigo Lara) Congressmen.
[camera clicks]
This is a disgrace.
These men, who became
inexplicably rich overnight have
reached this sacred institution
with their shady dealings.
Their presence in the house is
an insult to every Colombian.
[loud applause]
Congressman Escobar,
it certainly must have been
quite a struggle for you
to obtain your fortune
and to go from having a few
properties in Medellin to
accumulating more than
two billion dollars in
less than two years.
[loud applause]
Apparently, his honor the
Minister of Justice doesn't
believe that a person of humble
origin can, through hard work,
reach a higher social position
or a seat in this room.
Maybe you should question your
own presence here, Mr. Minister.
Because you don't believe in
the justice that you represent.
And you want the justice
system of another country for
our citizens. So you don't
deserve your position.
You should resign.
[smattering of applause]
You have lied today by
suggesting that my money's
linked to drug trafficking.
That's why I'm giving Your
Honor 24 hours to present solid
evidence of your
accusations against me.
Actually, you are the one who
should explain the origin of
the money that
financed your campaign.
[murmuring]
I will bring, I will
bring proof to this room of the
quantities that you and some
of your colleagues have received
from certain people.
Yes.
Unlike you, solid proof.
When, where, and how much.
Evidence.
Apparently Congressman Escobar
has detailed information about
how drug trafficking operates.
Which continues to surprise for
a humble and hardworking man
like himself.
[laughter, applause]
Pablo, resign! Leave!
Leave before they kick you out!
I want my son to see
me there, Victoria.
You don't want your
son to see what the whole
country saw today, Pablo.
Today. Those men clapping
in there today and laughing
in there today,
they have a lot to hide.
The President publicly
backed the Minister!
The President backs
the Minister because he has
a lot to hide, too!
So, what are you going to do,
accuse the President as well?
In front of the whole country!
Pablo, you're a drug trafficker.
Yes, and those bastards, they
stand up when I call them they
come to my parties, and they
grab every penny I gave them!
You promise me everything
will be all right.
Everything is fine.
I'm pregnant.
I don't want our baby to suffer.
He won't suffer.
Promise me it won't suffer.
...It won't...
Promise me or
I won't have it.
[phone rings]
Who's this?
I don't want a single
newspaper on the street!
I will pay 500 Pesos per copy!
Spread the word in the slums.
♪♪
(VO) El Espectador does a
cover story about the sins of
Pablo's youth backing
the Minister's accusations.
(VO) His criminal record
includes his involvement in the
murder of two
police officers in Leticia.
IN JAIL FOR DRUG CHARGES IN 1976
Goodbye career in politics.
(VO) The triggerman
Pablo sent to erase his past
didn't do his job.
He spent the money on women who
will not mourn his death today.
[loud barking]
[thwack, screaming]
[screaming, dog growling]
(Escobar) And since he's
such an important minister,
I have three different
operations prepared for him.
You want to know about them, I
let you know and you let me know
which one you like the most.
If you prefer not know
I'll do it anyway.
He's a minister, Pablo.
You can't kill a minister,
hombre.
No? Who says that? You?
(Garza) It's time to
start killing people,
so they learn to respect us.
Look, this is how it goes.
Every one of us put up ten
million pesos for expenses so
that way we are all committed.
Either we are all innocent
of we are all guilty.
That easy.
We're going to create a
company to kill a minister?
(man) In Cali, we don't want
to mix blood with business.
It complicates things.
Things are already complicated.
Haven't you noticed
up there in Cali?
In war you can't win
halfway, hermano.
There are no half
winners and half losers.
We have to go all the way in.
I mean, you people in Cali don't
like blood, then you'd better
not come to my
house to insult me.
Pablo, he didn't mean
to insult you, man.
Then I didn't mean to warn him.
Lara won't be in the
country for long.
They'll send him somewhere
as an ambassador.
Then you can kill him.
I was insulted by a
minister not an ambassador.
Do you want to hear the plans?
(Pelado)
Are they decided or what?
They think they are.
[chuckles]
Here.
What are we celebrating?
That everything is
going to change.
I want you to carry it
with you all the time.
All the time.
Oh, Pablo.
Open it.
Is this a joke?
It is not a joke.
Things are going to get
very complicated, Virginia.
Very.
I don't need a gun, Pablo.
Not me.
Ay, Virginia, I need you to
understand what's going to
happen that day
they come for you.
They will rip off your clothes,
that dress you're wearing now.
What is?
Thierry Mugler.
That one.
They will put it around your
ankles and they will hold you
down on the ground while many,
many soldiers take turns
to rape you.
They will bring them just for
you from the jungle, hungry for
a woman and they will get on you
one after another until they
tear your vagina to pieces and
then they will break bottles and
they will stick those broken
bottles in it and they will
stick blenders and hair dryers
and and they will turn them
on full blast
inside of you, yes.
And when you think you
are going to faint, they will
wake you up with cold
water so that you are awake for
the next group of soldiers.
Then they will let you bleed
till you die from inside.
This is why this is the best
gift I can ever give you,
my love. Take it.
If there are three coming at
you, take out the first one,
the one who's closest.
If there are four or more,
then...
Yes, you better kill yourself.
[crying] I want to go.
I want to go.
...Don't cry.
...I want to go.
Okay.
Okay. I'll take you home.
♪♪
(VO) The narco gives the boys
in the slums the education they
don't get from the government.
They don't mind dying if
they can leave 20 thousand to
their mothers because they
know that's more than they
will make in a lifetime.
[rapid gun fire]
(VO) To be a good sicario,
you have to be more than
just prepared to kill...
you have to be
prepared to die.
[cars honking]
[gun loading]
[shouting, honking]
[rapid gun fire]
And now, let's go to Cartagena
de Indias where they are
celebrating one of the
biggest events in Colombia.
No.
We've just received
a news update saying...
Saying that Minister of Justice
Rodrigo Lara Bonilla has been
assassinated only
minutes ago in Bogota.
In an emergency release, the
President Belisario Betancur has
called the Minister's murder
a crime against humanity...
(Pablo Jr) Mom. What's wrong?
...and declared the country
in a state of siege.
BREAKING NEWS
We'll be back with more
information as we compile more
facts about what happened.
Thank you.
[bell rings]
(VO) The government
takes on the Mafia.
President Betancur promises to
activate the extradition treaty.
The corporation relocates.
Where?
Where they keep the money.
The cartel proposes a
negotiation with the government
which sends an ex... president
to hear Pablo's proposal.
(Pablo)...at the present time
control roughly 80 percent
of global traffic.
We offer the repatriation of
our capital abroad to boost the
national economy and also pay
our country's external debt
presently estimated
at 12 billion dollars.
In exchange, we request amnesty
and the guarantee that under no
circumstances... no circumstances...
we will be extradited to another
country for any illicit
activities that may have
occurred to date.
(López... Michelsen) You know
things are very hot over there,
after the Minister.
Ah, yes, we were very sorry
to hear about that, sir.
(Velarde)
Listen closely before we go on.
Ex... president Michelsen
and myself are not here.
The president of the country has
not authorized this meeting.
This isn't happening,
is that clear?
(Ignacio Castro)
A timely clarification.
Much in the very same way that
my clients are sitting at this
table representing third
parties, rather than their own.
The extradition
part is nonnegotiable.
We can't guarantee
anything without the agreement
of our North American partners.
Ah, the North American partners.
They're gringos. Who needs them?
This is a matter
between Colombians.
You have to revoke that
extradition treaty.
Revoke it.
Go and tell your President,
the one you are
not representing here.
Yes, what's the other option?
War.
And we all know
what war is about.
The one who has
more cash wins it.
And look at us.
Who has more cash here?
♪♪
(VO) Pablo
couldn't keep his word.
His daughter is born
outside Colombia.
He holds the people
who drove him from
the country responsible.
The editor... in... chief of the
newspaper that published his
past gets killed.
[rapid gun fire]
[continuous car honking]
♪♪
Hello?
You're not carrying
the present I gave you.
Virginia, where is it?
I should have guessed when
I saw your boys downstairs.
No, no, my boys
are not downstairs.
You have so many agencies
following you that it is
impossible to park
on your street.
I'm used to men following me.
You are seeing someone else.
Don't forget that I listen
to your conversations.
You do?
Then you've heard the threats?
Since you started
killing ministers,
people keep calling me.
They turn on chainsaws, they
play funeral marches for me.
What happened to the Minister
was entirely his fault.
And what is going to happen
to this country now is the
government's fault.
It's not my fault.
And now the gringos want
to extradite me after Lara,
so we have to stop that
treaty no matter what.
And those of us who are in the
position to be extradited, we
are going to send a message to
the government and to the judges
and to the journalists.
It's gonna be fine.
Pablo, you are losing your mind.
Why?
You don't listen to anyone.
You think you can take on
everyone just by yourself.
You're headed
straight for suicide.
You're coming with me.
You'll be my
biographer, remember?
The one who will tell the story.
To whom?
There won't be anyone
left to hear it.
(Judge) No, wait, wait, wait.
Take that away.
You've got the wrong house.
Judge Carlos Alberto Alarcón?
That's me.
This is for you.
It's from Don Pablo
Escobar Gaviria.
[sharp exhale]
(VO) Pablo turns threatening
people into its own genre.
(Escobar) Oh, no, no, no.
Only one thousand million pesos!
Only! They're insulting us.
No, no, no, no.
This is what we'll do.
Hand out guns in the
slums, the more the better.
Two thousand guns, three
thousand guns, I don't care.
♪♪
For every dead cop, I
will pay 2,000 dollars!
And for every sergeant,
I will pay $5,000.
[gun shots]
For every lieutenant,
I will pay $10,000.
For every captain, $20,000.
For every army major, $50,000.
[gun shots]
To get paid, it's very easy.
They have to bring the
badge of the men they kill.
[phone rings]
[answering machine beep]
(VO) The law quickly sets its
exchange rate in the slums.
♪♪
[gun shots]
[gun shot]
(VO) Ten executions for
each dead police officer.
They see every teenage
boy as a future sicario.
(Escobar) I'm not asking you.
I'm ordering you.
I'm giving you 24 hours to do
what I say or I will kill your
mother, I will kill your father,
I will kill your grandmother.
(VO) Soon, all of those dead,
whether killed by Pablo or
his enemies will
haunt me as well.
(VO) The Colombian government
creates a special unit
exclusively for my boyfriend.
(Mendez) We're 500 men here,
all from Bogota devoted only
to capturing Pablo Escobar.
We can't take anyone from here.
We even bring in our own food,
so they won't poison us.
What makes the DEA
think we need you here?
Extradition Treaty
isn't working, is it?
So, if you don't send them up to
us, we come down and get them.
Nice.
(Santos) Using three receivers
on land we can precisely
calculate the signal
in a 200... yard radius.
If one of the posts detects
relevant information
it activates the protocol.
Hit the switch, you'll hear
a sound cue which will inform
your officer the
recording is in progress.
(Puppy Dog) Sir! Escobar!
He's in Sector 2, La Victoria.
It's a mobile line, sir.
(VO) The DEA set up
sophisticated tracking systems
to pinpoint Pablo.
[buzzer] Escobar!
He's having lunch at El Dorado.
It's a public phone, sir.
Sector 7, La Estrella.
That's on the other
side of the city.
[multiple buzzers]
(man) Escobar!
Is he everywhere?
(VO) They didn't take into
account the paisa astuteness.
(Slums Boy)
I saw Pablo at the corner.
On Bolivar Avenue.
[overlapping chatter]
(Director)
Nothing lasts forever, Virginia.
You know we have new partners,
and they have requested changes.
And your replacement, she has
the right people behind her.
Who she fucks is not the
problem, it's who I fuck.
Don't turn this
around, Virginia.
We don't care what you do
in your personal life here.
They told you to fire me.
Nobody told me to do anything.
It's an artistic decision.
Replacing me with that cheap
whore is an artistic decision!
Since when?
Say it.
Just say it.
This is because of him.
Say it.
Say it!
We don't care what that
gentleman lover of yours
does for a living.
No?
You might care from now
on, you motherfucker.
And you better watch out, 'cause
I'm gonna tell Pablo to blow up
your fucking building with
you and your family inside,
And that's gonna be an
artistic decision, too!
What's wrong with men?
Nobody ever told you that
if you want to see a woman,
you're supposed to call first?
Don't show me your badge.
I accept.
It's good news then.
Great news.
TV networks are like men...
sometimes you have to
leave them to be appreciated.
[chuckles]
So, what's your plan?
I have an offer from
a network in Florida.
I might take it.
Start a new life.
But I would need a man.
Are you still married,
Agent Shepard?
Until you've made love
to a Colombian woman...
that changes everything.
Please don't put my life
in danger, Virginia.
Pablo doesn't need an
excuse to kill a DEA agent.
He'll take you with
him when he goes down.
You know that, don't you?
Virginia,
you were fired by the network
and you don't have any offers.
No one will hire you.
Not here, not in Miami, nowhere.
You're marked, right, for life.
So you're gonna have to
find something else to do.
Anything.
And you're not 20 anymore.
Your legs aren't as pretty as
they used to be, or your smile.
What do you propose?
Help us.
In exchange for what?
Protection.
[huffs] Protection!
There is no such thing.
Pablo will find me
no matter where I go.
Do you think he
doesn't scare me?
You think all the threats and
death and smell of burnt flesh
don't affect me?
Help us find him.
You know what?
The TV networks only
want little girls now.
They don't value the
experience of a woman.
Is that what Pablo
values in you?
Exactly.
And my loyalty.
[snaps fingers]
The bill has been paid.
Wait here.
[car starts]
(Virginia) What all the gringos
want, Pablo, to catch you.
Is he staying in Medellin?
...Are you following me?
No, no, I'm not following you.
And what if I'm following you?
Do you have something
to hide, Virginia?
Pablo, don't follow me,
and don't call me anymore!
Okay? You are ruining my life.
You are ruining my life.
You know that I got
fired because of you!
People keep avoiding
me like the plague!
Nobody will come near me!
Well, that gringo have no
problem coming near you.
Stop talking about
him and listen!
Stay away from me!
I beg you! Stay away!
You're saying that because you
know they are recording this
and you want them to think
it is over between us.
Aahh! It is over between us!
Hear it, it is over!
If anyone's out there
listening, please record this!
I have nothing to do
with the psychopathic killer
on the other side of the line!
Listen, I call you back.
I call you back.
Aarghh!
(Girl) Do you like birds?
Yes, they represent freedom.
(VO) Pablo's lovers... teenage
girls from poor neighborhoods
handed over by their families
for a few thousand pesos.
It isn't easy sleeping with
the most wanted man in Colombia
and keeping it a secret.
Believe me, I know.
It just takes
one of them to talk
to have the
Search Bloc find him.
[sighs]
[people shouting]
Oh, God.
[gun fire]
[rapid gun fire]
[helicopter spooling down]
[girl screams]
[explosion]
[sobbing]
(Monje) Listen,
I need to reach Pablo.
Our people in Miami are
getting out of line.
The routes are falling apart,
and the Cali Cartel is getting
our territory!
We can't finance this war
if the business stops
working, you understand?
I don't want you to kill them.
They're our link up there.
I just want you to find Pablo.
Is that so difficult
to understand to you?
[gun shot]
(VO) Monje's death
meant the fall of the
cartel's financial wing.
Garza's death meant the
fall of the toughest wing.
[rapid gun fire]
Pablo loses his strong men.
From this point on,
he can only run.
(Escobar) For years we have
called for peace, but the only
response we've gotten has
been official and systemic
persecution against our
families and organizations.
KEEP HIM ON THE LINE That's why I declare
full out war on the government and the
political establishment.
If they make me run,
I make them run too.
Terrorism is the atomic
bomb of the poor.
ONE MORE MINUTE
We're not using lead anymore.
From now on, we're using
dynamite, understand?
(Announcer) And how do we know
that you are really Pablo
Escobar Gaviria and not someone
else pretending to be him?
That is very easy.
I will prove it to you by
killing you and your family
tonight, and blowing
up your radio station.
What do you think?
Would that be enough?
Hey!
(Producer) You're a celebrity
in your country, Virginia.
What's so appealing about coming
to Miami to host a TV show?
Well... I don't really
think I have anything
else to prove in Colombia.
No?
But I guess what appeals
to me is the challenge,
the excitement
of a new adventure.
Also, there are some very
attractive men in this
part of the world.
Tell us, Virginia, what's
the last show you hosted on
Colombian TV?
(Agent) How you doing?
FBI.
Mind if we take a
look at your passport?
You carry any money?
My ex isn't using
me as a mule, yet.
Okay.
(Woman Reacting) Oh, my God!
What happened?
I'm sorry, they just
closed Bogota Airport.
Why?
I'll call you back.
An Avianca plane
exploded in midflight.
[woman sobbing]
(VO) After the first bombs,
the country asked the government
to give Pablo hell.
(VO) After a dozen bombs,
the country begs the government
to give Pablo what he wants.
[explosion, screams]
Pablo!
[sirens wailing]
(Santos) Newell.
There was a Newell in
my graduating class.
You think it could be him?
What is it?
List of victims on
the Avianca flight.
107 people on board.
They just sent it.
Robin Newell and
Catherine Gilmore.
35, 32 years old.
Married.
(Secretary) Sir?
Sir, wait.
Ambassador, there were two
Americans on the Avianca flight.
So, listen, directive 12.333
authorizes military operations
in foreign countries to
guarantee the security of
American citizens...
(Williams) Thank you, Sarah.
Agent Shepard, I'm sure
you know Mr. Velarde.
He's also the man in charge
of negotiating the surrender
of Pablo Escobar.
This is Mr. Castro.
He's Mr. Escobar's
legal representative.
He's agreed to turn himself
in to the authorities.
In exchange for what?
By revoking the Extradition
Treaty, our judges and
magistrates have taught the
world a lesson in sovereignty,
independence and patriotism.
After years of persecution...
♪♪
(VO) Pablo adds one last
condition to his surrender.
He provides the prison.
♪♪
(Escobar)
It is very pretty, isn't it?
(VO) He cedes the property to
the municipality through a front
man so they can build it there.
Everyone's here
but the President.
He couldn't make it.
Scheduling problems.
(VO) Without the threat of
extradition hanging over him
Pablo needs a safe place to
reorganize his business.
(VO) And the government
provides him with one.
(Santoro) The Conception
and Norman Key routes are
working again. The Fany is
at almost one hundred percent.
We have 250 planes in service
and 30 Pipers still
immobilized in Santamarca.
Are you talking to the number
two at the Aviation Authority?
Talk to him, he's a brother.
If he doesn't want to play
ball you bring him
here and I talk to him.
So, for everyone who is still
outside nobody moves a gram
without me knowing it.
Nobody. Understood?
They have to pay the
taxes that they owe me.
That's 20 percent.
...20 percent?
...20 percent.
They won't like that, Pablo.
The Cali people are
asking for five percent.
Jesus, everyone will
go to them and that's OK.
How do you know that?
Have you talked to them?
You prefer those
pussies from Cali,
go to them and try your luck.
I came up with the routes, I
took out extradition all by
myself so you can keep working.
So make everybody knows that the
one who hasn't paid with cash,
merchandise or properties
will pay with his life.
What's next?
♪♪
(VO) Soccer players from the
professional league come to
play with the traffickers.
♪♪
(VO) And the match isn't
over until the Patrón wins.
[cheering]
The social workers have arrived!
♪♪
(VO) Sundays are
saved for family.
(Manuela) Why don't you
live at home with us, Daddy?
Because I work here, Princess.
My princess.
This is my castle. I...
Do you see those
towers there?
Those are my towers.
I am a king, and
king has castles.
And that's why
you are a princess,
because you are my daughter.
But there are guards.
Yes, of course there are.
They are here to protect me.
Mommy says you can't leave,
and she cries all the time.
What do you mean I can't leave?
Who says that?
Mommy.
This is my castle.
I can come and go as I please.
You wanna see that?
You want to go out
for an ice cream?
Where is the place that the
big park near the church.
That's the one you like.
Let's go.
What did you have for lunch?
Good Lord.
Don't wait for us.
Manuela and I are going
out for an ice cream.
Pablito still has
his sense of humor.
Who's in charge of this castle?
Who's the boss here?
(Guard) You, Patrón.
Yeah, that's what I like
to hear. Open the door.
Open the door!
(Escobar) Open it.
The king and his princess are
going out for an ice cream.
What flavor you want?
...Strawberry!
Strawberry!
The princess has a craving!
If you dare to stop us, the
king will cut your heads off.
Open the door.
Our carriage is waiting for us.
Give me the keys.
Give me the keys, man.
The king is asking for
the keys of the car.
Give me the keys.
Give me the keys, man!
(Victoria) Pablo!
Pablo!
I forgot to tell you,
my princess, that...
I made them bring
the best ice cream,
strawberry ice cream
of the world here for you.
Strawberry ice cream just made
with ice from the North Pole
which is especially for
my daughter my princess,
especially!
The best one in the world!
For you.
(Manuela) Really?
Have you heard of the strawberry
icebergs in the North Pole?
They're very famous.
(VO) Not only has
the media banned me.
My advertising contracts are
also cancelled which forces me
to sell my home to pay my debts.
Be careful with that!
What you just moved with your
foot is a very expensive piece
of Indonesian art.
I'm not asking you
to use your head.
Using your hands will be enough.
(VO) I rent an apartment at El
Nogal where a former First Lady
lives, hoping her bodyguards
will keep an eye on me as well.
How are you boys?
(Man) Fine, thanks.
(VO) And I get a break
from the telephone threats.
(Technician) All set, ma'am.
[phone rings]
Wasn't it a new number?
(VO) But not for long.
[door opens]
Nice hotel!
How's our book going?
What book?
Who would want to
read a book about you?
I have my admirers.
Your admirers can't
read, they're too young.
That's true.
That's one of their virtues.
You know that I left
a meeting to see you,
so, what do you want? Tell me.
I need to know if I'm safe.
And how would I know that?
No one is safe in this country.
As far as you're
concerned, can I feel safe?
No!
Nobody will kill their own
biographer, don't worry.
Relax.
What else?
Oh, Pablo.
You can't imagine how
terrifying my life has become.
My phone won't stop ringing.
Threats, every day,
threats. You have an army
of men to protect you,
but who protects me?
What about me?
What can I do?
I need you to tell everyone
we are not together anymore.
You're breaking my heart.
After all that
I've done for you.
What have you done for me?
Nothing!
I already had a
career when I met you.
Don't forget that.
And I'm the only woman who has
loved you without expecting
anything in return and
that includes your wife.
No, no, no, no, no.
Don't you ever dare
to compare to my wife.
Don't even put the name
of Victoria on your lips.
She was with me when
I didn't have a peso.
Would you have
noticed me back then?
With no planes and no trips
and no shopping in New York?
Would you have?
No, tell me, would you?
I don't think so.
I'm broke, Pablo!
I'm broke! My career
is over because of you!
Nobody will hire me
anymore because of you!
So you need to help me!
How? What do you need?
Tell me.
What do you need, Virginia?
80 thousand dollars
to go to Europe.
80 thousand dollars.
That's a lot of money.
I don't have that money.
No, I don't.
And you are my biographer,
you have to stay here.
[gasp]
I've seen things, Pablo.
I've seen things.
While I was with you.
You've seen what?
Things that implicate
a lot of people!
If I wanted to talk!
[laughs]
If you what?
No, no, no, no!
No, I never expected
this from you. Really.
My God, that's not what I mean!
Pablo, I would never betray you!
It's just that I'm desperate!
I don't even know what
I'm saying anymore!
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Don't worry.
Don't worry, I will
take care of you.
I will protect you.
I'll make sure you
have a long life.
You want to know what?
I have bad news for you.
Nobody will get near you
because they will be afraid
that I will kill them.
So your life is going
to be full of shit.
[whimpering]
[door slams]
[sobs]
♪♪
(Escobar) Peladito.
[laughs]
(Santoro) The things are
getting rough out there, man.
Business, business
isn't good, man.
No, they're not good, no.
One question the Fany route
moves, what, 10 kilos a month?
Yeah.
And you pay me,
what 50 thousand?
50 thousand?
The Fany route
failed twice this month.
We lost two 600... kilo shipments.
We have to pay the owners,
hire lawyers for the pilots.
Yeah, yeah, but the
deal was 250, no?
I gave you that route, remember?
250 is impossible, Pablo.
Is impossible, I mean it.
Trust us.
We are your partners,
you son of a bitch.
We've been together
from the start.
Well, we're not
in this together.
I'm here and you're out.
Yeah, we know that, Pablo.
But you have to pay me the tax.
So...
You have to.
Either you pay it, or
I double it right now.
We have to discuss it
with the other families.
Business has changed a lot.
Things aren't the same
they used to be anymore.
50 thousand should be enough.
So you come here to
sit down in front of me
with that gold and
those fancy clothes.
You're all getting rich
out there, while I am here.
No, no, no, Pablo.
And then you're flirting
with the Cali people.
And to top it off, you
don't want even to pay me.
♪♪
[screaming]
No, no, don't complain.
Don't complain.
You are already dead.
This is just a formality.
This way your families can
put the pieces back together.
[chainsaw roaring]
♪♪
(VO) The murders at La Catedral
reached the media and make the
government an accomplice.
[explosion]
Its credibility is at stake.
They decide to transfer
Pablo to a military prison.
(VO) The fence of
the prison was electric
but the switch
was in Pablo's room.
(La Plaga) Our people are
turning on us, Patrón.
Apparently, they're
thinking, if he did that to
Santoro and Hermosilla,
what will he do to us?
Running like chickens
straight to Cali.
What, do you think
that was a mistake?
(VO) Sure it was.
Pablo's ex... associates
cooperate with the government
in exchange for having
their records cleared.
Dozens of narcos willing
to fight hinn are released.
(Ignacio Castro)
To the airport.
Son, say goodbye.
This is not a country,
it's a mass grave.
[yelp]
Hey hey hey!
Who are you?
What the fuck do you want?
[crack]
[squealing tires]
(VO) Pablo's enemies,
members of rival cartels,
and paramilitary groups
together with government
security forces supported by
the DEA and the CIA formed
the most lethal hunting
party of all time.
(VO) The bodies of Pablo's
lawyers, hitnnen, accountants,
and family appear
scattered all over Medellin.
[screams]
(VO) Anyone who's ever been
close to him becomes a target.
[door buzzer]
(Buyer) Good morning.
Can I help you?
Good morning.
These belonged to
European royalty.
And these earrings.
If you give me a good
price, I bring you more.
Okay. Let me have a look.
Exquisite.
[knocks on window]
Don't open the door.
...Do you know him?
...No.
Call the police.
[door buzzer]
Call the police!
[clanking]
...I'm sorry.
No! What are you doing?
I don't want to get in trouble.
Sorry.
Let me in! Let me in!
Let me in!
[muffled] Let me in!
No no nooo!!
[muffled gun fire]
[panicked screaming]
[wailing]
[car starts]
[panting]
♪♪
I'm going to be a star.
Look.
Victoria, do you hear that?
Manuela's gonna be a
star in a Christmas show.
Will you come and see me?
Yes, I will.
Mom made me a shiny costume.
I am sure you're
beautiful in it.
Don't cry. Don't cry.
She won't be in the show.
What?
Why?
The parents of the other
children objected.
They held an assembly.
She doesn't know yet.
Why?
Because they're afraid your
enemies will blow up the school,
Pablo, that's why.
They are scared.
Give me your hand.
I need you to take the kids,
get in a plane and get
out of this country.
It's getting very
dangerous for you here.
You can't stay here.
You can't.
So, once you leave I
can take care of things.
You didn't keep
your promise, Pablo.
You promised me
everything would be fine.
I know.
That my children would
have a normal life.
Does this seem like
a normal life to you?
[door closes]
There's a woman out here,
she wants to talk to you.
What's her name?
I don't know. She got
mad at me when I asked.
Says she's famous around here.
He needs to get his
family out of the country.
They cannot stay here.
They would reach them
in America, so they
have to go to Europe.
And as soon as they are out,
he'll feel free to
destroy everything.
So you cannot let them leave.
As long as they are here, he'll
be busy trying to protect them.
You better trust me.
You can't let them leave.
This is his weak spot, his
family, his family, his family.
It's all he cares
about, nothing else.
And you know that
firsthand, don't you?
No you have no idea.
(Velarde) We can't do that.
The Attorney General is the one
getting them out of the country.
They made a deal.
Once they're out, Pablo
Escobar will turn himself in.
Break your word.
Let's put some pressure
on the German Chancellor.
They land in Cologne
in two hours.
Do not let them
get off that plane.
There's no legal reason they
can't travel to Germany.
Bring them back.
The family is bait.
We need them alive and at home.
Put them someplace,
and we sit and we wait.
Pablo will try to
talk to them, right?
When that happens,
we'll be ready.
(Newscaster) Pablo Escobar
Gaviria's family was greeted by
a strong security presence
upon arrival in Bogota this
morning after being
denied entry into Germany.
The wife and the two children
of the couple were forced to
spend the night in Cologne's
airport, and later sent back
to Colombia on a regular...
They have taken
my family hostage!
...that the family
requested upon arrival.
The Army has cordoned off
the apartment building where
they are staying.
The operation has been joined
by men from the Fiscalía
and the Search Bloc.
Juan Pablo, please turn it off.
(Woman)
Do you need anything else?
No, thank you.
Pablo!
Thank you very much.
You're welcome.
I should've asked if
anyone wanted anything.
[phone rings]
Hello?
(Agent) Call!
(Escobar)
Victoria, what happened?
Are you okay?
Is everyone okay?
(Victoria) They treated
us well, my love. Don't worry.
You have to be careful, okay?
How are they?
How are you? How is Manuela?
How's Manuela?
She's okay, my love.
She's okay.
You're all we
think about, Pablo.
We miss you so much.
When you come and go,
are they protecting you?
Are they holding you hostage?
(Victoria)
There's an army outside.
(Agent) Puppy Dog, do you read?
The man is on the phone.
La América sector.
I repeat La América sector.
(Agent) We're on our way, sir.
Ask the Attorney
General to release you.
Yes, Attorney General.
Yes, only I take care of
my family, nobody else.
Nobody else, okay?
[click]
Hello.
Anybody listening?
Two minutes, Patrón.
Ay, ay, ay.
I know that you are
all there listening.
Hiding like a
bunch of fucking pussies.
The Colonel and his
Bloc trash, and all of you
And the CIA, and that
motherfucker from the DEA.
I already spared your life once.
I won't spare it again.
You hear me?
Now listen to me,
motherfuckers, everyone.
I'm going to kill you and your
children and your wives and I'm
saving a special bullet to put
right in front of your fucking
skull and you're going
to bleed until you die!
Don't call here anymore, mister.
This place is full of cops...
Victoria, don't
tell me what to do.
No, no, no, don't
Nobody ask you.
Yes, yes, keep Manuela nearby.
[disconnect tone]
Stay calm, Patrón.
Go check. Go check.
Hold on.
(VO) The previous moment
to something happening
is always the best moment.
Like when you are waiting
for the nnan you love
or when you are about
to open a present.
The fishermen from the
coast of Colombia
say that what really
matters is the wait.
Feeling the sea breeze on your
face, the salt on your lips.
Imagining that little fish
fucker approaching the bait.
He wants to bite it,
but he thinks it over.
But if the bait is good enough,
the fish will
eventually bite it.
Even when he knows
there is a hook inside...
he'll bite.
[dialing]
[connect tone]
(Agent) Call!
(Manuela) Daddy?
Manuela.
How is the most
beautiful star in the sky?
Mommy says I can't
be in the show.
Mommy's wrong.
Mommy's saying that because
she wants it to be a surprise.
Don't tell her that
I told you that.
(Puppy Dog)
I'm getting a signal.
Somewhere in Los Olivos,
between 80 and 90th.
(Mendez)
Los Olivos, 80 and 90th.
[squealing tires]
And you have your dress ready?
It's all shiny, Daddy.
Beautiful.
Everything's going to be much,
much better from now on,
you will see.
My love you will see.
Correction.
70 and 80.
[squealing tires,
honking horns]
Will you come and see me?
Yes, I will. Of course.
Will they let you?
They? They will.
Of course they will.
And you know why?
Because you're the king?
Yes, I am the king.
72 and 80th.
74 and 80th.
...He's to my left!
50 meters!
Turn here!
Sweetheart, put Juan Pablo on.
I just saw him!
We got him!
Inform the President!
Dad?
Patrón, two minutes.
...Mijo, ou are now
the man of the house.
Now you have to take care
of your mother and Manuela,
...Okay.
...Okay, I have some notes
for you to tell the press.
Go ahead.
Write it down, write it down.
Okay, the Attorney General
agreed on getting you out of
the country, but they didn't do
it because they gave into the
pressure of my enemies in
Colombia and out of Colombia.
Tell them that Pablo Escobar
agreed on turning himself in the
moment his family was safe but
they didn't keep their side of
the deal, and now they will
have to pay the consequences.
...Move in!
Whatever happens from now
on is gonna be their fault.
Okay? Repeat what I said
back to me, Juan Pablo.
[door crashes]
No, no, no, no, no.
No, that's not what
I said, Juan Pablo.
That's not what I said. I said
that they are responsible for
all of this, and that they have
to face the consequences now.
Okay, Dad.
I'm going to hang up.
...You tell that son of a bitch...
[muffled shouting]
Say it!
Listen, you have to learn this!
If you can't get people
to like you then you have
to make them respect you!
And if they don't respect
you then make them fear you!
Understand?
Make them fear you!
Do you hear that?
[bonking]
[cocks gun]
Hold on.
Dad?
[explosion, gun fire]
[distant dog barking]
Long live Colombia!
...Long live Colombia!
[bonking on walls, gasp]
[gun shots, scream]
Long live Colombia!
(Newscaster) A last minute wire
confirms that Pablo Escobar
Gaviria, the ex... boss of the
Medellin cartel has been gunned
down today by members of the
Search Bloc in a residential
neighborhood of Medellin.
Along with Escobar,
police also killed Carlos
Mejía Rosales alias Pelao.
Virginia.
You ready?
I'll wait for you outside.
♪♪
Do you still love him?
I love Pablo.
I hate Escobar.
Would you be willing to testify
before a Federal judge?
He asked me to tell his story.
He just didn't say who to tell.
♪♪